TUDOR FIL

Ale. Valea Calugareasca Nr. 3, Bucharest, Romania · +40729106339

tudor@tudorfil.ro · http://www.linkedin.com/in/tudor-fil/ · @tudorfil

Experienced Senior Consultant with a demonstrated history of working in the information technology and services industry. Extensive exposure to different technologies, cultures and work environments.

Bringing value, leadership and efficiency to the automated infrastructure and cloud services business models.

EXPERIENCE

OCT 2018 – PRESENT

SYSTEM ENGINEER, NETCENTRIC SRL (COGNIZANT)

Concurrent with previous expectations, a relationship with the client is developed during the implementation. If the project allocation is standard, above business acumen and relationship management, technical key responsabilities include:

Implementation and operation of enterprise scale system environments Implementation, integration and operation of large-scale AEM (CQ) set-ups Implementation, integration and operation of large-scale webserver set-ups feasibility analysis

Be able to work collaboratively from various locations

Travel to other Netcentric offices and customer sites as required.

APR 2017 - OCT 2018

SENIOR CONSULTANT, DELOITTE DIGITAL

Client level consultancy services, functional and operational.

Leadership and goal setting sessions with a team of 5 counselees with a focus on Personal and Professional Improvement, Educational Strategy, Goal Setting and Appraisals, Knowledge Transfer, Collaboration and Communication skills.

Ownership and Consultancy work for business partners. Involvement in all phases of project delivery from design and architecture to implementation, operation and maintenance.

Tools development and documentation to support complete application lifecycle based on last

Tools development and documentation to support complete application lifecycle based on IaaS, IaC and Microservices models in a Service Oriented Architecture (SOA) approach.

Implementation of industry specific tools with the purpose of providing a mature DevOps offering, based on Continuous Deployment and Continuous Integration philosophies with the end goal of 1-Click deployments, Hot Patching, Short Disaster Recovery, Data Security, GDPR, ISO 27001, PCI DSS Compliance and Shorter Time to Market.

Work in a cross disciplinary environment as an integral part of Feature Teams, in an Agile manner with an accent on deliverable quality and adherence to timelines.

Evaluate and improve existing infrastructures against ITIL best practices.

Tudor Fil | tudor@tudorfil.ro | +40 729 106 339 | @tudorfil

Present and educate Functional Teams about the DevOps philosophy, tools and approaches in contrast or as an enhancement to standard software development practices and delivery models.

JUL 2015 - APR 2017

PRINCIPAL MEMBER OF TECHNICAL STAFF, ORACLE SYSTEMS

Support and improve Oracle's RightNow platform, part of the Oracle Service Cloud Offering. Provide expertise and guidance, as a senior member of the newly created DevOps team.

Evangelize DevOps tools and practices and an Agile approach.

Manage a CentOS based, multitenant cloud infrastructure.

Introduced RunDeck and DevOps tools to the existing toolchain.

Built an automated deployment process for existing containers.

Respond to service requests within company's SLAs.

Develop tools and provide documentation and support for various teams that use the developed automated tools.

APR 2014 - JUL 2015

DEVOPS, IBX BUSINESS NETWORK - CAPGEMINI

Develop and improve automated infrastructure and processes, for faster and efficient deployment lifecycle.

Continuous integration and toolchain support for Feature Teams across organization and projects.

Architect and implement automation solutions spanning multiple projects/ products for complete release support, from infra provisioning, to app deployment and testing. Working with ControlTier/Chef/Jira/Jenkins/VMware/Linux/Windows/PowerShell/Ruby and BASH.

SEP 2013 - APR 2014

SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR, BITDEFENDER

Antispam Labs uses a complex architecture of mail servers and queueing services to deliver its service.

Design and propose improvements and upgrades to the existing infrastructure taking into consideration the specific needs of the project.

Implement plan to upgrade and execute on-line switchover to new infrastructure in secondary datacenter.

Provide system administration services for Linux / UNIX / Windows infrastructure and development systems (scripting, load machines, system configuration);

Ensure systems are kept in required configuration profile, including: maintenance, changes as required by evolvement of production environments, updating software and software configurations;

Troubleshoot Linux / Windows systems identifying hardware, software (both OS and application level), and networking issues.

Performing specific failure recovery procedures for managed systems and applications.

APR 2011 - AUG 2013

TELECOM ENGINEER, ADOBE SYSTEMS

Provide technical and operational support for all adobe offices in EMEA.

Global coverage as secondary duty. (EMEA has around 15 offices with around 3500 users)

Tudor Fil | tudor@tudorfil.ro | +40 729 106 339 | @tudorfil

On call response for service outages and emergencies.

Project work for system enhancements and maintenance.

Provide on demand services for research teams.

Working with cisco infrastructure (Gateways/ PBX/Phone/Routers) working with Call Manager 7.x/8.x and Unity.

Working with convergent technologies (Cisco Unified Communications/Cisco Unified Presence Server)

Cisco Jabber (Android/iOS/ Blackberry) managed deployment, profiling and configuration.

Experience with Route Patterns/ Dial plans/ International Routing/ CAC /RegExp. programming.

Working with Exchange 2010 and Active Directory.

PKI Infrastructure and deployment.

Working with different Linux distributions depending on need. CentOS/ Ubuntu

Server installations/troubleshooting.

Build/maintain monitoring solutions for IDC/MDC and Demo Labs for High

Availability readiness.

APR 2010 - APR 2011

DESKTOP SUPPORT TECHNICIAN, ADOBE SYSTEMS

Provide local support for all finance and engineering staff on campus

Provide on demand services for research teams.

Includes installing networking hardware, rack-mounting. Server installations/troubleshooting. Build/maintain monitoring solutions for IDC/MDC and Demo Labs.

JAN 2008 – JAN 2010

SYSTEMS ADMINISTRATOR, HATCH LTD.

Administer a Linux Networx HPC CFD modeling cluster based on Suse Linux ES server 10. (Ansys, Fluent, Gambit)

Developed an automated provisioning model for all compute nodes, with on demand reprovisioning and host based access across all nodes. Similar to Ansible, but in BASH.

Administer a render farm, based on Windows XP SP3 and Cinema 4D.

Developed manual provisioning model for all compute nodes based on Windows Remote Management services.

Responsible with the maintenance of one of the major project offices of the company, (office has 260 users).

Supporting the company's major clients.

Complete the necessary paperwork for purchases, and keep a buffer inventory updated.

Respond to all support calls either for walk-in, email or phone, within the company's SLAs.

Coordinate with vendors and suppliers, to keep the inventory updated

EDUCATION

JULY 2005

TELECOM TECHNICIAN, PTTR – MAIL AND TELECOM COLLEGE - BUCHAREST

Vocational College Diploma

JULY 2008

OSSD, NTCI – TORONTO

Ontario Secondary School Diploma

SKILLS

- Autodidact and efficient learner
- Strong Technical Abilities
- Strong communication and language skills
- Strong leadership and ownership
- Teaching, Guidance and Counseling
- Proven Technical and Business Experience

TOOLS

- RunDeck, Jenkins, ControlTier
- Chef, Ansible, TerraForm, Docker
- AWS, ESXI, Vsphere, KVM, XenServer, Rackspace
- GIT, SVN, SourceTree
- APIs, Scripting, REST, SSL Certs, Vulnerability Scanning, Package Management, Alerting and Monitoring, Incident Management, GDPR guidelines.
- Linux, Windows, RedHat, CentOS, Gentoo, Ubuntu, Slackware, Mandriva/ Mandrake.
- IPTables, IPFW, pfSense, IPv4, IPv6, Routing, OSI Layers, NIS, LDAP, SSL, SSH, SELinux, AppArmor, SAMBA, NFS, NAS, SAN, RAID, iSCSI.
- BASH, Python, Ruby, PowerShell, BAT, Excel, VCL, TCL Expect, JSON.
- NAS, Blades, HP switches, Cisco routing, Cisco voice hardware.

ACTIVITIES

- 2012 ITIL Foundation Certification
- **2010** RHCE (Red Had Certified Engineer)
- 2008 FIRST Fellow Team member

APMG-International

RedHat Inc.

For Inspiration and Recognition of Science and Technology Non-Profit

HOBBIES

- Self-Improvement and Education
- Driving
- Cycling
- Trekking
- Traveling

Tudor Fil | tudor@tudorfil.ro | +40 729 106 339 | @tudorfil

Electronics and Automation

Attending courses on Coursera, Google Developer Program, Lynda.

I own a Mazda Miata NB.

I cycle to work and back and maintain an overall

healthy addiction to cycling.

Currently working on a home automation project based on ESP32 and Arduino hardware.